<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cv url="cv.xml" css="cv.css"
    icon="https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/63b93bd070e5048ad604b9805b97ce1d.png"
    pdf="cv_cecile_tonglet.pdf"
    website="www.cecton.com">
  <card>
    <firstname>Cécile</firstname>
    <surname>Tonglet</surname>
    <email>cv@cecton.com</email>
    <birth>age 32</birth>
    <address>
      <cp>1390</cp>
      <city>Grez-Doiceau</city>
      <country>Belgium</country>
    </address>
    <languages pre="Languages:">
      <language level="5. Native">French</language>
      <language level="4. Full professional proficiency">English</language>
      <language level="1. Elementary proficiency">Dutch</language>
    </languages>
    <!--
    <mobile>+32 (0) 4...</mobile>
    <phone>+32 (0) 2...</phone>
    -->
    <note>European Driving Licence B</note>
    <links>
      <column>
        <a href="http://github.com/cecton">GitHub</a>
        <a href="http://gitlab.com/cecton">GitLab</a>
      </column>
      <column>
        <a href="http://be.linkedin.com/in/cecton/en">LinkedIn</a>
        <a href="https://twitter.com/CecileTonglet">Twitter</a>
      </column>
      <column>
        <a href="http://blog.cecton.com">Blog</a>
      </column>
    </links>
  </card>
  <title name="C&#x00e9;cile Tonglet">
    <subtitle>
      <line>CTO &amp; Senior Software Engineer</line>
      <line>Rust&#xa0;&#x2013; React</line>
    </subtitle>
  </title>
  <!--
  <word>&#x201c;You never finish a program, you just stop working on it.&#x201d;</word>
  -->
  <section title="Experience" description="Career path">
    <subsection title="Charlin" description="01.2019 &#x2013; 08.2019">
      <text>
        I'm building an engineering team with a strong culture based on trust and efficiency.
        Optimized for asynchronous work and emphazing code ownership, responsibility, decision making and freedom of choice.
      </text>
      <text>
        Technologies: AWS (IoT, Lambda, RDS, Fargate, CloudFront), Terraform,
        React.js, Node.js, Python.
      </text>
    </subsection>
    <subsection title="Collibra" description="09.2018 &#x2013; 12.2018">
      <text>
        Helping on frontend development.
      </text>
      <text>
        Technologies: React, TypeScript, Relay, Jest, Enzyme and WebPack.
      </text>
    </subsection>
    <subsection title="TenForce" description="09.2017 &#x2013; 08.2018">
      <text>
        I'm rewriting completely the front-end of the TenForce Web application
        to make it fast, responsive and easier to maintain.
      </text>
      <text>
        Technologies: React, TypeScript, Redux, redux-observable, RxJS, Jest
        and WebPack.
      </text>
    </subsection>
    <subsection title="TenForce" description="04.2016 &#x2013; 08.2017">
      <text>
        Working on semantic technology, I made backends for OAuth login,
        Docker Compose &amp; Swarm backend and a few various libraries.
      </text>
      <text>
        I'm also in charge of the DevOps work part of our department:
        continuous integration tools, automatic deployment &amp; packaging,
        etc... I'm always proposing new ideas to improve our processes and
        development environments.
      </text>
      <text>
        Technologies: Terraform, Scala, Docker, Docker Compose, Docker Swarm,
        Node.js, Python 3 (with asyncio), Open Stack.
      </text>
    </subsection>
    <subsection title="Codabox" description="08.2015 &#x2013; 03.2016">
      <text>
        In an almost flat organization, I analyze the needs and implement various
        new business logics to our internal softwares including: a REST API,
        reporting tools and core business services. Part of my role is also to
        maintain our infrastructure and find solutions to our common issues.
      </text>
      <text>
        Technologies: Docker, Python, Django, Django REST framework, HTML5.
      </text>
    </subsection>
    <subsection title="Odoo" description="02.2012 &#x2013; 07.2015">
      <text>
        One of my job is to manage a development team, maintain a platform for
        the migration services (with web services) and provide some support
        when the tickets need a deeper expertize.
      </text>
      <text>
        I developed from scratch the migration platform using Python, Odoo
        and Docker in order to make the deployment much easier. My target was
        to make a distributed system where workers are located on AWS that can
        scale depending on the load. I'm still receiving really good feedbacks
        of my work today by my former colleagues.
      </text>
    </subsection>
    <subsection title="YCare" description="05.2011 &#x2013; 11.2011">
      <text>ORM with customized Web application to manage a travel agency and orders from the website.</text>
      <text>Software/Languages: Apache Web Server, MySQL, Perl, DBI, XML/XSLT</text>
      <text>Tasks: requirements analysis, database design, framework design, customized scripts and web design.</text>
    </subsection>
    <subsection title="La Fonderie" small="a.s.b.l." description="01.2011 &#x2013; 04.2011">
      <text>Database development.</text>
      <text>Software: FileMaker Pro</text>
      <text>Tasks: script creation and server maintenance.</text>
    </subsection>
  </section>
  <section title="Skills" description="A brief summary" class="nb">
    <abilities>
      <label>Languages</label>
      <ability>Rust, Scala, JavaScript, Haskell, Python 2/3, Perl, Bash, C++</ability>
      <label>Frameworks</label>
      <ability>Django, asyncio/aiohttp, Odoo, Play, Qt, Flask, Ember.js, GTK+, Tk</ability>
      <label>Databases</label>
      <ability>PostgreSQL, MySQL, Virtuoso, SQLite</ability>
      <label>JavaScript</label>
      <ability>TypeScript, React, Redux, RxJS, Jest, WebPack, Hapi</ability>
      <label>Technologies</label>
      <ability>
        Serverless, Docker, React, Amazon&#xa0;Web&#xa0;Services, Python Async
I/O, XML, SDL2
      </ability>
      <label>OS</label>
      <ability>ArchLinux, (WSL), Gentoo, Debian, RedHat, OpenSUSE, SailfishOS</ability>
      <label>Graphism</label>
      <ability>The Gimp (retouching), Inkscape (vector), AutoCAD (CAD)</ability>
    </abilities>
  </section>
  <section title="Work Quality" description="What I am really good at" class="nb">
    <abilities>
      <label>Effectiveness</label>
      <ability>
        I try to choose the path that will bring more effective results in my management and decision making process.
      </ability>
      <label>DevOps</label>
      <ability>
        Excellent at scripting and automation. I like the things to work out of
        the box without any hassle. I believe every project should get
        continuous integration and proper review.
      </ability>
      <label>Analysis</label>
      <ability>
        Getting a quick grasp on unfamiliar codebases, revealing issues,
        performance analysis and profiling, code simplification, optimization
        and readability.
      </ability>
      <label>Maintainability&#xa0;&amp;<br />Robustness</label>
      <ability>
        Finding the simplest and most reliable solution to a given problem
        without losing sight of the fact that every code need to evolve.
        Fully document it and comment it as much as necessary.
      </ability>
      <label>Testing</label>
      <ability>
        Test-driven development. I like to have a strong test environment
        including unit and integration tests. I will, however, debate if I believe some tests aren't bringing any value to the application.
      </ability>
      <label>Team Working</label>
      <ability>
        I like to share my knowledge and I am very patient and easy to work with.
      </ability>
    </abilities>
  </section>
  <section title="Training" description="Studies" class="nb">
    <abilities>
      <label>2005&#xa0;&#x2013;&#xa0;2006</label>
      <ability>Sciences informatiques<br/>Universite Libre de Bruxelles</ability>
      <label>2002&#xa0;&#x2013;&#xa0;2005</label>
      <ability>Sciences &amp; Informatique,<br/>Institut Provincial d'Enseignement Technique, Nivelles</ability>
    </abilities>
  </section>
  <section title="Hobbies" class="nb">
    <text>
      I sometimes help nonprofit organization to set up their work
      environment.
    </text>
    <text>
      I am autodidact. Most of my knowledge come from my own passion for
      programming and computer in general by reading books.
    </text>
    <text>
      I am enthusiastic about embedded systems, I own two WRT routers,
      Raspberry Pi (1 and 2), a Cubieboard and a
      <a href="https://www.crowdsupply.com/sutajio-kosagi/novena">Novena</a>.
    </text>
    <text>
      I like doing my own stff. I made a game system capable of playing a bunch
      of old retro consoles (mostly 8 bits and 16 bits). I also own a few
      consoles of my youth: the Sega Saturn (which I modded a bit) and a Sega
      DreamCast.
    </text>
  </section>
  <section title="Social Skills" description="Way of working" class="nb">
    <columns>
      <column>
        <li>Team player</li>
        <li>Client focused</li>
      </column>
      <column>
        <li>Like to share knowledge</li>
        <li>Love to learn</li>
        <li>Autodidact</li>
      </column>
      <column>
        <li>Listening</li>
        <li>Autonomous</li>
      </column>
    </columns>
  </section>
</cv>
